Mearat Hou

Phone: +61 421 230 310Website: https://www.mearat.comEmail: mearatjames@gmail.comGithub: https://github.com/mearatjames

Located: Long Beach, CA 90807 **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/mearat-hou-013a93164

Motivated web developer with experience in building and maintaining high traffic web pages. Strong collaboration skills and special interest in building scalable web applications and integrating modern UI/UX responsive design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN Stack, MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.Js, Vue.Js, JAM Stack, JavaScript, Gatsby, GraphQL, Netlify CMS, SVN, Git, MySQL, Firebase, HTML5, CSS3, the command line, computer science fundamentals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hogarth Australia,

Greater Sydney, Australia — Frontend Web Developer

JAN 2020 - Present

- Localized and maintained web pages for the Australia and New Zealand market for one of the biggest global tech companies.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility, web accessibility, and responsive design according to the brief and requirements from the client while also meeting tight deadlines.
- Developed electronic direct mails (EDMs) that were sent out to millions of customers.
- Assisted lead developer in building an internal web application to improve producers workflow efficiency.
- Conducted training and on-boarding new developers to ensure consistent coding standards and following client's guidelines.

Hogarth Worldwide,

Sunnyvale, CA — Frontend Web Developer

AUG 2019 - DEC 2019

- Maintained client digital assets using clean, accessible mark-up according to the latest web standards.
- Coordinated with interactive producers, project managers, graphic production artists, copy editors and QA for the web pages implementation.
- Used SVN for Version Control and client's proprietary project management tools to collaborate with other developers and stakeholders.
- Investigated and resolved QA tickets through the communication with the QA team.

Center for Inherited Blood Disorders,

Santa Ana, CA — *Wholesale Program Coordinator*

JAN 2017 - AUG 2019

- Built a web application to parse csv files and generate inventory, chargebacks, and sales reports.
- Worked closely with the cloud ERP system vendor to customize the wholesale system.
- Built pharmacy order templates using excel formulas to help improve workflow efficiency and accuracy.
- Created wholesale training instruction modules to facilitate fellow coworkers and new trainees.

EDUCATION

UC Irvine Division of Continuing Education

Irvine, CA — Full Stack Web Development

JUL 2018 - JAN 2019

National University of Management

Phnom Penh, Cambodia — Bachelor of Business Management

OCT 2007 - SEP 2011